const e="We could not find what you asked for, but got you this",o="chemistry",t=200,i=120,a=[{id:151,question:"The allotrope of carbon used in the decolourization of sugar is",option:{a:"Graphite",b:"Soot",c:"Charcoal",d:"Lampblack"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:162,question:"An isomer of C5H12 is",option:{a:"Butane",b:"2-methylbutane",c:"2-methylprpane",d:"2-ethylbutane"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:36,question:"When chlorine is passed into water and the resulting solution exposed to sunlight, the product formed are",option:{a:"Chlorine gas and hydrogen",b:"Oxygen and oxochlorate(l) acid",c:"Hydrochloric acid and oxygen",d:""},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:288,question:"To a solution of an unknown compound, a little dilute Tetraoxosulphate (IV) acid was added with some freshly prepared (II) Tetraoxosulphate (VI) Solution. The brown ring observed after the addition of a stream of concentrated  Tetraoxosulphate (VI) acid confirmed the presence of",option:{a:"CI",b:"SO",c:"NO",d:"CO"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:137,question:"A carcinogenic substance is",option:{a:"Asbestos dust",b:"Sawdust",c:"Nitrogen(II) oxide",d:"Carbon (II) oxide"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:64,question:"A gas X diffuses twice as fast as gas Y under the same conditions. If the relative molecular mass of X is 28. Calculate the relative molecular mass of Y",option:{a:"120",b:"14",c:"56",d:"112"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:45,question:"Which of the following gases contains the least number of atoms at s.t.p",option:{a:"4 moles of chlorine",b:"3 moles of ozone",c:"1 mole of butane",d:"7 moles of argon"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:24,question:" 2SO2(g) + O2(g) ⇌  2SO3(g)  The equilibrium constant for the reaction above is increased by  [ΔH = -189kJ mol -1]",option:{a:"Increasing the temperature of the system",b:"Increasing the pressure of the system",c:"The addition of a catalyst to the system",d:"Increasing the surface area of the vessel"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:73,question:"The gas that gives brown colouration in brown ring test",option:{a:"Co2",b:"NO2",c:"NO",d:"CO"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:149,question:" N2O4(g)    ⇌  2NO2(g)",option:{a:"A constant volume",b:"An increase in pressure",c:"A decrease in pressure",d:" A decrease in volume"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:267,question:"The stability of the noble gases is due to the fact that they",option:{a:"Have duplet or octet electron configurations",b:"Belong to group zero of the periodic table",c:"Are volatile in nature",d:"Have no electron in their outermost shells"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:84,question:"A gas exerts pressure on its container because",option:{a:"Some of its molecules are moving faster than others",b:"Of the collision of the molecules with each other",c:"Of the mass of the molecules of gas",d:"The molecules of a gas collide with the walls of the container"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:157,question:"Alloys are best prepared by",option:{a:"Electroplating",b:"Arc-welding",c:"Reducing a mixture of their metallic oxides",d:"Cooling a molten mixture of the metals"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:303,question:" Two hydrocarbons X and Y were treated with bromine water. Decolorized the solution and Y did not. Which class of compound does Y belong",option:{a:"Alkynes",b:"Alkenes",c:"Alkanes",d:"Benzene"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:58,question:"The solubility of a salt of molar mass 101g at 200C is 0.34mol dm-3. If 3.40g of the salt is dissolved completely in 250cm3 of water in a beaker, the resulting solution is",option:{a:"Unsaturated",b:"A suspension",c:"Saturated",d:"Supersaturated"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:294,question:"The residual solids from the fractional distillation of petroleum are used as",option:{a:"Raw materials for the cracking process",b:"Fuel for driving tractors",c:"Fuel for jet engines",d:"Coatings for pipes"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:168,question:"In the production of soap, concentrated sodium chloride solution is added to",option:{a:"Increase the solubility of the soap",b:"Decrease the solubility of the soap",c:"Saponify the soap",d:"Emulsify the soap"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:120,question:"The process by which atoms are rearranged into different molecular structures in the petroleum refining process is referred to as",option:{a:"Catalytic cracking",b:"Hydrocracking",c:"Polymerization",d:"Reforming"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:175,question:"N2(g)  +  3H2(g)  ⇌   2NH2(g)   Δ H = - 90kJ  In the equation above, the yield of ammonia can be decreased by",option:{a:"Adding a catalyst",b:"Removing ammonia",c:"Increasing the pressure",d:"Increasing the temperature"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:33,question:"During the vulcanization of rubber, sulphur is added to",option:{a:"Break down rubber polymer",b:"Lengthen the chain of rubber",c:"Bind rubber molecules together",d:"Act as a catalyst"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:219,question:"Zinc and carbon rods are used as anode and cathode respectively in a",option:{a:"Voltaic cell",b:"Lead accumulator",c:"Leclanche cell",d:"Daniel cell"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:222,question:"In the electrolysis of CuSO4(aq) using platinum electrodes, the reaction at the anode is",option:{a:"4H+  +  4e-  → 2H2",b:"2OH  +  2OH-  →  2H2O + O2",c:"2OH-  - 2e-    → 2OH",d:"4OH-  -  4e- →  2H2O + O2"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:65,question:"A fixed mass of gas has a  volume of 92cm3 at 30C. What will be be its volume at 180C if the pressure remains constant",option:{a:"15.3cm3",b:"87.3cm3",c:"97.0cm3",d:"552.0cm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:86,question:"The weakest attractive force that can be observed between two molecules is",option:{a:"Ionic",b:"Covalent",c:"Coordinate covalent",d:"Van der Waals"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:191,question:"The component of an atom that contributes least to its mass is the",option:{a:"Nucleus",b:"Neutron",c:"Electron",d:"Proton"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:261,question:"Which of the following is an example of a mixture",option:{a:"Blood",b:"Sand",c:"Washing soda",d:"Common salt"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:293,question:"Stainless steel is used for making",option:{a:"Tools",b:"Coins and medals",c:"Moving parts of clocks",d:"Magnets"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:55,question:"Tetraoxosulphate(VI) acid burns the skin by",option:{a:"Heating",b:"Hydration",c:"Dehydration",d:"Hydrolysis"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:125,question:"If a solution contains 4.8g of Tetraoxosulphate (VI) acid. Calculate the amount of copper(II) oxide that will react with it  [CU = 64, O = 16, S = 32, H = 1]",option:{a:"0.8g",b:"4.0g",c:"40.0g",d:"80.0g"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:205,question:"When water boilers are used for a long period of time, the solid substances left behind as scale are",option:{a:"Magnesium trioxosilicate (IV) and calcium Tetraoxosulphate(VI)",b:"Magnesium trioxosilicate(IV) and rust",c:"Clay and magnesium trioxosilicate (IV)",d:"clay and rust"},section:"",image:"",answer:"",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:142,question:"The oxidation state of chlorine in HClO4 is",option:{a:"-5",b:"-1",c:"1",d:"7"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:46,question:"A compound contains 31.91% potassium, 28.93% chlorine and the rest oxygen. What is the chemical formular of the compound",option:{a:"KCLO3",b:"KCLO4",c:"KCLO",d:"KCLO2"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:255,question:"In the industrial production of H2 from natural gas, the CO2 produced along with the H2 is removed by",option:{a:"Passing the mixture into lime water",b:"Washing under pressure",c:"Drying over phosphorous(V)oxide",d:"Using ammoniac copper(l) chloride"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:139,question:"Calcium Tetraoxosulphate(VI) dissolves in water only sparingly to form a",option:{a:"Solution",b:"Suspension",c:"Precipitate",d:"Colloid"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:280,question:"6AgNO3(aq)  +  PH3(g) +    3H2O(l)      →    6Ag(s)+   H3PO3(aq)   +    6HNO3(aq)  In the reaction above, the reducing agent is",option:{a:"H2O(l)",b:"PH3(g)",c:"AgNO3(aq)",d:"HNO3(AQ)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:77,question:"What is the percentage by mass of oxygen in Al2(SO4)3.2H2O",option:{a:"14.29%",b:"25.39%",c:"50.79%",d:"59.25%"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:269,question:"Elements in the same periodic table have the same",option:{a:"Atomic number",b:"Chemical properties",c:"Physical properties",d:"Number of shells"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:83,question:` I.  H = 1s1
II. O = 1s22s22p4
III. N = 1s22s22p3
IV. Zn = 1s22s22p63s23p64s23d10
From the above, which of the following pairs is likely to be paramagnetic?
`,option:{a:"I and II",b:"I and  III",c:"I    and IV",d:"III  and IV"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:121,question:"Which of the following is found in cotton",option:{a:"Starch",b:"Cellulose",c:"fat",d:"oil"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:19,question:"A metal M displaces zinc from zinc chloride solution. This shows that",option:{a:"M is more electronegative than zinc",b:"Zinc is above hydrogen in the series",c:"M is more electropositive than zinc",d:"Electrons flow from zinc to M"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:166,question:"The reaction above is",option:{a:"Carboxylation",b:"Decarboxylation",c:"Acidification",d:"Esterification"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:196,question:"In the purification of impure samples of ethyl ethanoate synthesized by esterification, concentrated sodium trioxocarbonate(IV) solution is used to remove",option:{a:"Water",b:"Acidic impurities",c:"Basic impurities",d:"Ethoxyethane"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:5,question:"An oxide X02 has a vapour density of 32. What is the atomic mass of X [O = 16]",option:{a:"32",b:"20",c:"14",d:"12"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:133,question:"Chlorine consisting of two isotopes of mass numbers 35 and 37 in the ratio 3:1 has an atomic mass of 35.5. Calculate the relative abundance of the isotope of mass number 37.",option:{a:"20",b:"25",c:"60",d:"75"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:165,question:"Vulcanization involves the removal of",option:{a:"A monomer",b:"The single bond",c:"The double bond",d:"A polymer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:60,question:"which of the following chlorides would exhibit the least ionic character",option:{a:"AlCl3",b:"CaCl2",c:"MgCi2",d:"LiCl"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:54,question:"The furring of kettles is caused by the presence in water of",option:{a:"Calcium trioxocarbonate(IV)",b:"Calcium tetraoxosulphate(VI)",c:"CALCIUM HYDROXIDE",d:"Calcium hydrofentrioxocarbonate(IV)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:260,question:"Which of he following pairs of substances will react further with oxygen to form a higher oxide",option:{a:"SO2 and NO",b:"CO2 and H2O",c:"CO and CO2",d:"NO and H2O"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:62,question:"The processes which return carbon(IV) oxide to the atmosphere include",option:{a:"Photosynthesis, decay and respiration",b:"Photosynthesis, respiration and transpiration",c:"Respiration, decay and combustion",d:"Ozone, depletion, combustion and decay"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:185,question:"The density of a certain gas is 1.98g dm-3 at s.t.p. What is the molecular mass of the gas   [Molar volume of a gas at s.t.p = 22.4dm-3]",option:{a:"26.0g",b:"31.0g",c:"54.0g",d:"44.0g"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:278,question:"The colour of methyl orange in alkaline medium is",option:{a:"Pink",b:"Orange",c:"Red",d:"Yellow"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:290,question:"A constituent common to moist air, it gradually rusts. This is due to the formation of",option:{a:"Silver",b:"Copper",c:"Tin",d:"Lead"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:145,question:"In the electrolysis of brine, the anode is",option:{a:"Platinum",b:"Copper",c:"Zinc",d:"Carbon"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:18,question:"P(g) + O(g)    ⇌ 3R(s)  +  S(g)   ΔH is negative which of the following will increase the yield of R",option:{a:"Using a larger closed vessel",b:"Increasing the temperature",c:"Removing some S",d:"Adding a positive catalyst"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:141,question:"What volume of 0.5mol dm-3 H2SO4 will exactly neutralize 20cm3 of 0.1 mol dm-3 NaOH solution",option:{a:"2.0cm3",b:"5.0cm3",c:"6.8cm3",d:"8.3cm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:29,question:"NH3(g)  +  HCI(g)  → NH4CI(s) The entropy change in the system is",option:{a:"Negative",b:"Indeterminate",c:"Positive",d:"Zero"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:200,question:"Natural water collected from rivers and ponds contains oxygen, carbon(IV) oxide and",option:{a:"Chlorine",b:"Hydrogen",c:"Sulphur(IV) oxide",d:"Nitrogen"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:204,question:"The air around smelting industries is likely to contain",option:{a:"CO2, SO3 and H2",b:"SO2N2 and CO2",c:"H2, SO2 and CO2",d:"H2S, CO and N2"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:150,question:"Which of the following shows little or no net reaction when the volume of the system is decreased",option:{a:" H2(g)  +  l2(g)  ⇌  2Hl(g)",b:"2NO2(g)  ⇌  N2O4(g)",c:" PCl5(g)   ⇌ PCl3(g)  + Cl2(g)",d:" 203(g)   ⇌  3O2(g)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:12,question:"Pure solvents are obtained by",option:{a:"Distillation",b:"Condensation",c:"Extraction",d:"EvapopraTION"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:11,question:"Deliquenscent substances are used for",option:{a:"Cooling",b:"Wetting",c:"Melting",d:"Drying"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:4,question:"Cancerous growths are cured by exposure to",option:{a:"ɣ-rays",b:" β – rays",c:" ἀ – rays",d:"X -rays"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:99,question:"When at equilibrium, which of the reactions below will shift to the right if the pressure is increased and the temperature is kept constant",option:{a:" 2SO3(g)  ⇌  2SO2(g)  +  O2(g)",b:" 2CO2(g)  ⇌ 2CO(g)  +  O2(g)",c:" 2H2(g)  +  O2(g) ⇌  2H2O(g)",d:" 2NO(g)   ⇌ N2(g)  +  O2(g)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:20,question:"Which of the following best explains the increase in the rate of a chemical reaction as the temperature rises",option:{a:"The bonds in the reacting molecules are more readily broken",b:"The molecules collisions become more violent",c:"A lower proportion of the molecules has the necessary minimum energy to react",d:"The collision frequency of the molecules increases"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:113,question:"Carbohydrates are compounds containing carbon, hydrogen and oxygen in the ratio",option:{a:"3:01:01",b:"2:01:01",c:"1:02:01",d:"1:01:01"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:237,question:"Which of the following has an isomer",option:{a:"C4H10",b:"C6H6",c:"C2H4",d:"C2H6"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:207,question:"In which of the following reactions can the oxidation number of nitrogen be said to have increased",option:{a:"FeSO4(aq)  +  NO(g) →   Fe(NO)SO4(S)",b:"2NO(g)  +  O2(g) → 2NO2(g)",c:"NO(g)  +  CI2(g)  → NOCI2(l)",d:"NO(g)  +  Br2(l)   → NOBr2(l)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:275,question:"Carbon (II) oxide is considered dangerous if inhaled mainly because it",option:{a:"Competes with oxygen in the blood",b:"Competes with carbon (IV) oxide in the blood",c:"Can cause lung cancer",d:"Can cause injury to the nervous system"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:91,question:"What mass of K2CrO4 is required to prepare 250cm3 of 0.020 mol dm-3 solution   [K2CrO4 = 194.2g mol-1]",option:{a:"0.97g",b:"9.70g",c:"19.42g",d:"97.10g"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:268,question:"The maximum number of electrons in the L shell of an atom is",option:{a:"8",b:"18",c:"32",d:"2"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:68,question:"A rock sample was added to cold dilute HNMO3. The gas evolved was passed into a solution of acidified K2Cr2O7 and the solution turned green. The rock sample contains",option:{a:"NO3-",b:"Cl-",c:"SO42-",d:"SO32-"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:6,question:"Milikan’s contribution to the development of atomic theory is the determination of",option:{a:"Charge on electron",b:"Positive rays",c:"Charge to amss ratio",d:"Cathode rays"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:244,question:"The produce of the combustion of candle wax are",option:{a:"Carbon(IV) oxide and water",b:"Oxygen and water",c:"Hydrogen and water",d:"Carbon(II)oxide an d water"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:102,question:"When sugar is dissolved in tea, the reaction is always accompanied by",option:{a:"Positive entropy change",b:"Negative entropy change",c:"No entropy change",d:"A minimum entropy change"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:214,question:"2H2 + O2  → 2H2O  ΔH = -571Kj  In equation above, how much heat will be liberated if 12.0g of hydrogen is burnt in excess oxygen?",option:{a:"-1713kJ",b:"+1142kJ",c:"-571kJ",d:"-1142kJ"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:103,question:"Which of the following is an electrolyte",option:{a:"Alcohol",b:"Sodium acetate solution",c:"Solid potassium hydroxide",d:"Mercury"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:17,question:"In which of the following reactuions does reduction take place",option:{a:"Fe2+ - e-   Fe3+",b:"2O2-  → O2 + 4e-",c:"Cr - 2e-  → Cr2+",d:"2H+  +  2e-   →H2"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:232,question:"The element with the electron configuration 1s22s22p3 is",option:{a:"Oxygen",b:"Chlorine",c:"Nitrogen",d:"Calcium"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:252,question:"Carbon exists naturally in the combined state as",option:{a:"Diamond",b:"Coal",c:"Wood",d:"Graphite"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:43,question:"Which of the followinig respresents hybridization in ethyne?",option:{a:"Sp2",b:"Sp2d",c:"Sp3",d:"sp"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:52,question:"The substance least considered as a source of environmental pollution is",option:{a:"Silicate minerals",b:"Uranium",c:"Lead compounds",d:"Organophosphorous compounds"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:140,question:"Which of these compounds is a normal salt",option:{a:"NaHS",b:"NaSO4",c:"NaHCO3",d:"Na2CO3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:3,question:"A particle that contains 9 protons, 10 neutrons and 10electrons is a",option:{a:"Neghative ion",b:"Positive ion",c:"Neutral atom of a non metal",d:"Neutral atom of a metal"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:167,question:` Alkanol + Alkanoic acid ⇌  Ester + water.
The reverse reaction of the equation above is known as
`,option:{a:"Hydrolysis",b:"Saponification",c:"Hydration",d:"Fermentation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:63,question:"Which of the following statements is true of a proton.",option:{a:"The total mass of the protons in a particular nucleus always half the nuclear mass",b:"The mass of a proton is 1840 times the mass of an electron",c:"The mass proton is 1.0008g",d:"The mass of a proton is one-twelfth the molar mass of carbon"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:228,question:"The volume of 2.5 moles of oxygen at s.t.p is",option:{a:"56.0dm3",b:"84.0dm3",c:"50.0dm3",d:"20.0dm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:230,question:"2C2H2(g)  +  5O2(g)     4CO2(g)  +  2H2O(g) In the reaction, the mass of carbon (IV) oxide produced on burning 78g of ethyne is [C = 12, O = 16, H = 1]",option:{a:"39",b:"352g",c:"264g",d:"156g"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:118,question:"Ethanol reacts with excess acidified K2Cr2O7 to produce",option:{a:"Ethanoic acid",b:"Ethanol",c:"Ethyl ethanoate",d:"Ethanoic acid"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:272,question:"Substances employed as drying agents are usually",option:{a:"Hygroscopic",b:"Efflorescent",c:"Acidic",d:"Amphoteric"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:101,question:` CO(g) + H2O(g) ⇌  CO2(g)  +  H2(g)
From the reaction above, calculate the standard heat change if the standard enthalpies of formation of CO2 (g), H2O (g) and CO (g) in kJ mol-1 are -394, -242 and -110 respectively.
`,option:{a:"-262 kJ  mol-1",b:"-42kJ mol-1",c:"+42 kJ mol-1",d:"+262 kJ mol-1"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:152,question:"Which of the following gases can be collected by the method of downward delivery",option:{a:"Chlorine",b:"Oxygen",c:"Ammonia",d:"Hydrogen"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:97,question:"Which of the following will change when a catalyst is added to a chemical reaction",option:{a:"The activation energy",b:"The potential energy of the reactants",c:"The heat of reaction",d:"The potential energy of the products"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:154,question:" sulphur (IV) oxide bleaches by",option:{a:"Reduction",b:"Oxidation",c:"Hydration",d:"Absorption"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:279,question:"Which of the following salts is slightly soluble in water",option:{a:"CaSO4",b:"Na2CO3",c:"PbCl2",d:"AgCl"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:108,question:"The salt that will form a precipitate soluble in excess ammonia solution is",option:{a:"Ca(NO3)2",b:"Cu(NO3)2",c:"Mg(NO3)2",d:"Al(NO3)3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:35,question:"A trihydric alkanol is",option:{a:"glycerol",b:"phenol",c:"glycol",d:"ethanol"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:240,question:"CH3-CH2-C = CH  The hybridization in the compound above is",option:{a:"Sp3 and sp",b:"Sp3 and sp2",c:"Sp",d:"Sp2"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:161,question:"The alkyl group can be represented by the general formula",option:{a:"CnH2n+1",b:"CnH2n",c:"CnH2n+2",d:"CnH2n-2"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:169,question:"The gas that can be dried using concentrated Tetraoxosulphate (VI) acid is",option:{a:"Ammonia",b:"Hydrogen bromide",c:"Sulphur (IV) oxide",d:"Hydrogen sulphide"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:172,question:"In a flame test for calcium, the flame appears",option:{a:"Blue when viewed through a blue glass",b:"Green when viewed through a blue glass",c:"Orange-red when viewed through a blue glass",d:"Brick-red when viewed through a blue glass"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:248,question:"An emulsion may be produced by shaking a detergent solution with",option:{a:"Palm wine",b:"Palm oil",c:"Ethanoic acid",d:"Water"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:173,question:"Which of the following alloys contain iron",option:{a:"Steel and permalloy",b:"Duralumlin and steel",c:"nd Soft Solder a Duralumlin ",d:"Brass and bronze"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:117,question:"The type of reaction that is peculiar to benzene is",option:{a:"Addition",b:"Hydrolysis",c:"Polymerization",d:"Substitution"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:28,question:"In which of the following reactions has the oxidation number of nitrogen increased",option:{a:"2NO(g)  +  Br2(l)  → 2NOBr(l)",b:"2NO2(g)  +  O2(g)   → 2NO2(g)",c:"FeSO4(aq)  +  NO(g) → Fe(NO)SO4(s)",d:"2NO(g)  +  CI2(g) →  2NOCI(l)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:119,question:"A compound contains 40.0% carbon, 6.7% hydrogen and 53.3% oxygen. If the molar mass of the compound is 180, find the molecular formula  [H = 1, C = 12, O = 16]",option:{a:"CH2O",b:"C3H6O3",c:"C6H12O6",d:"C6H6O3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:144,question:"Which of the following acts as both a reducing and an oxidizing agent",option:{a:"H2",b:"SO2",c:"H2S",d:"CO2"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:48,question:"A little quantity of Trichloromethane (b.pt.600C) was added to a large quantity of ethanol (b.pt.780C). the most probable boiling point of the resultant mixture is from",option:{a:"699C – 700C",b:"820C – 840C",c:"600C – 780C",d:"700C – 744C"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:147,question:` 2CO(g)  +  O2(g) →  2CO2(g)
Given that   Δ H [CO] is 110.4kJ mol-1 and Δ H [CO2] is -393.0kJ mol-1, the energy change for the reaction above is
`,option:{a:"-503.7kJ",b:"-282.6kJ",c:"+282.6kJ",d:"+503.7kJ"},section:"",image:"",answer:"N",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:49,question:"The chromatographic separation of ink is based on the ability of the components to",option:{a:"React with each other",b:"React with the solvent",c:"Dissolve in each other in the column",d:"Move at different speeds in the column"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:265,question:"Moving from left to right across a period, the general rise in the first ionization energy can be attributed to the",option:{a:"Increase in nuclear charge",b:"Decrease in screening effect",c:"Increase in screening effect",d:"Decrease in nuclear charge"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:178,question:"The most suitable metal that can be used as a lightening  conductor is",option:{a:"Aluminium",b:"Iron",c:"Copper",d:"Silver"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:156,question:"Aluminium hydroxide is used in the dyeing industry as a",option:{a:"Salt",b:"Dye",c:"Mordant",d:"Dispersant"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:111,question:"The modern process of manufacturing steel from iron is by",option:{a:"Treatment with acids",b:"Oxidation",c:"Blast reduction",d:"Treatment with alkalis"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:134,question:"Which of the following mixtures of gases is likely to burn in flame",option:{a:"Neon and hydrogen",b:"Nitrogen and helium",c:"Helium and neon",d:"Neon and nitrogen"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:194,question:"How many hydrogen atoms does a single ring cycloalkane have less than the corresponding open- chain alkane",option:{a:"Three",b:"One",c:"Four",d:"Two"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:138,question:"The solubility in mol dm-3 of 20g of CuSO4 dissolved in 100g of water at 1800C is  [Cu = 64, S = 32, O = 16]",option:{a:"0.13",b:"0.25",c:"1.25",d:"2"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:184,question:"A heterogeneous mixture can be defined as any mixture",option:{a:"Whose composition is uniform",b:"Whose composition is not uniform",c:"Formed by solids and liquids",d:"Of a solute and a solvent"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:197,question:"A substance that is used as a ripening agent for fruits is",option:{a:"Propene",b:"Methane",c:"Ethene",d:"Butane"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:66,question:"The postulate of Dalton’s atomic theory which still holds is that",option:{a:"Particles of different elements combine in a simple whole number ratio",b:"Atoms can neither be created nor destroyed",c:"The particles of the same element are exactly alike",d:"All elements are made of small indivisible particles"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:122,question:"the principal constituent of natural gas is methane",option:{a:"ethane",b:"propane",c:"butane",d:"butane"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"}],n={message:e,subject:o,status:200,total:120,data:a};export{a as data,n as default,e as message,t as status,o as subject,i as total};
